DANIE MICHELE DIBADJOU

Frederick, MD 21701 | 804-924-5050 | niatoned@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/niatoned LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/danie-dibadjou-

4ab4ab115/

Web developer with 3+ years of experience in designing, implementing, testing and debugging web sites and applications using best practices. Bringing forth experience in using modular, object oriented programming to develop new features and ensure optimization contributing all through the development life cycle and workflow efficiencies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Tools: HTML/JavaScript/CSS, TailWindCss, Laravel7, Symfony3, Java5, NodeJs, Bootstrap,

Jquery, Ajax, LiveWire, Gwt, Wordpress, Git, SCRUM, TDD, CI/CD

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

- ❖ Web developer and pre-sale technician 05/2017 to 06/2018 Adwa Sarl Douala, Cameroon
 - Working as part of the team for the web integration of an online transport ticketing app (www.kiwoti.cm)
 - Managed and maintained clients websites

Key Accomplishments:

- Help migrate actual code to version 5 of PHP and use OOP practises
- Help implements MVC design pattern for better code structure and future maintenance
- Create clients websites using wordpress
- Working on web services for our electronic payment API
- **Symfony2 developer** 05/2016 to 06/2017

Itech Sarl – Douala, Cameroon

• In charge of the development of an e-commerce back-office

Key Accomplishments:

- Managing products
- Managing orders
- Enhancing store design
- o Design the functionality to manage all the images and their appearance on the site
- ❖ Gwt junior developer 04/2014 to 10/2015

Bao Sarl – Bangangte, Cameroon

• My developer workflow: --> Pick a new task online on Jira server planning board --> Read the task description and agree with the team master about the feature involved. --> Create a new git branch to work on. --> Launch eclipse --> Write the acceptance (cucumber/selenium) to validate the feature involved by the task --> Design and implemented the front-end of the functionality if needed. --> Implement the Unit test that will validate the Back-end of the functionality. --> Implement the back end code and run the related Unit test. --> Run the acceptance and ensure everything work well. --> Push code to Gitlab server for integration. --> The push launch a build on Jenkins (CI) that build and test the new feature. --> When Jenkins builds succeed, I mark the task as resolved on Jira and set the amount of time spend in from eclipse. --> I create a Merge request in Gitlab to ask the team master/reporter to validate my work(the new feature) --> The team master/reporter check the feature and decide if it is okay or not.

PROJECTS:

www.kiwoti.cm is a ticketing web and mobile application to book car, bus, train and plane trips

- Integrate the template using PHP and enhance some frontend features
- Working on payment gateway including several payment methods
- Tools / languages used: PHP4-5, MySQL, Bootstrap4, HTML, REST API, Javascript, Ajax

www.laravel.cm Laravel community's website in Cameroon

- Working closely with the community manager and lead developer to move from bootstrap to TailwindUi
- Working on Tutorial and blog module
- Tools / languages used: Bootstrap, Laravel, Livewire, TailwindCss, MySQL

www.fredcleaning.com My cleaning company website to book house cleaning services

- Build and hosting of a simple website to show cleaning services and enable online booking
- Tools / languages used: Bootstrap, Laravel

EDUCATION:

Bachelor of Science: Information Systems and Operation Management **University of Douala** - Cameroon